Dictionnaires de langue en ligne
================================

English-Spanish Spanish-English English-Italian Italian-English English-French French-English English definition English thesaurus Español-Français Français-Español Español-Português Português-Español Español: definición Español: sinónimos

×

WordReference Privacy Policy
----------------------------

WordReference.com is deeply committed to protecting the privacy of Internet users. Below is information outlining our continued support for the responsible management of consumer information.   
  
**Consumer Information**  
WordReference.com does not collect any personally identifiable information about you such as your name, address, or phone number. E-mails are used only for login if you register as a member of the forums. WordReference does not sell your email address or use it for advertising. However, WordReference.com does obtain some types of non-personally identifiable information such as your browser type (Chrome or Safari, for example), the type of operating system you use (Macintosh or Windows, for example), and/or your IP address. The information collected by WordReference.com is used for the purpose of troubleshooting, targeting ads and measuring ad effectiveness on behalf of advertisers.  
  
In some cases, we will also collect information on your preferred target language for translations and search history. This is used only for making the site easier to use and possibly for ad targeting.

**Cookies**  
WordReference uses "cookies" to enhance the user experience, such as remembering your favorite dictionary, counting visitors through tracking, and tracking by online advertisers. If you wish to use WordReference without cookies, major web browsers like Chrome and Firefox have add-ons that allow you to block them. By not blocking them and continuing to use this site, you are consenting to their use. If that is not good enough for you, then please do not use this free website; we suggest that you may wish to purchase a paper dictionary instead. Please note: all of our competitors also use cookies.

**Third Party Advertising**  
Much like Google and Facebook, WordReference gets its revenue from and would not exist without advertising. We use a number of third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our website. When you visit our website, we may collect your IP address and/or information about your browser or operating system, and we may share it with these companies. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please go to [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices). If you live in the EU, please see [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

**Third Party Cookies**  
In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertisers may place or recognize a unique "cookie" on your browser. Cookies might also be used by other companies, such as Facebook.com. We use analytics software such as Google Analytics to count our visitors.  
  
Third-party advertising companies may also create a pseudonymous ID for the purpose of recognizing you anonymously on your devices. The ID does not contain any of your identifiable personal data. We may place this ID in our first-party cookie or use a partner that places a third-party cookie and allows it to be used for online and cross-context advertising. This ID may be shared by us or on our behalf with our advertising partners and other third-party advertising companies for the purpose of enabling interest-based content, profiling, and/or targeted advertising throughout your online experience. One such third-party company is ID5. Detailed information on ID5's data processing activities in connection with this ID and ID5’s opt-out is available [here](https://id5-sync.com/privacy) and in ID5’s platform privacy policy here: [https://id5.io/platform-privacy-policy](https://id5.io/platform-privacy-policy).

**Forum user tracking**  
Spam and trolls are major problems in the forums. To keep the site enjoyable and safe for all users, we log IP addresses from registration and posting messages and save old email addresses of registered forum members. This information is invaluable for the security of the site and its members. We generally do not retain IP logs of unregistered visitors for more than 30 days.

**Cookies and Opt Out**  
If you do not want the benefit of cookies, there is a simple procedure to manually delete your cookies. Please search the web to find out how. If you wish to opt out of data collection, please refer to the link above. There are also web browser add-ons that can accomplish this and even keep cookies from WordReference and other sites and advertisers that you choose off of your browser. If you want to hide your IP address, please instead use the Tor Browser to visit WordReference.  
  
If you have any additional questions about WordReference.com's dedication to consumer privacy, please write to the site administrator through the "Contact Us" form in the [WordReference language forums](https://forum.wordreference.com/misc/contact).  

**GDPR**  
Change your GDPR consent settings.
